foopets.com 2011-12-28

# FooPets | Real Virtual Pets Online

Updated April 19, 2011

We're excited about your interest in FooPets, and that you've chosen to adopt one of the world's cutest and most realistic, interactive 3D pets! On FooPets, children (and people of all ages) learn responsible pet care as they feed, pet, water and play with their puppy or kitten daily, in a safe online environment. 

FooPets welcomes parents, guardians, teachers and other adults participating in their children's online activities. Foopets.com is owned and operated by Rivet Games, Inc. located at with offices at 625 2nd St, Suite 104, San Francisco, California 94107, USA. On this site, children can participate in a virtual online environment and adopt and take care of a virtual pet. Children are given the opportunity to adopt a pet from one of several breeds of dogs and cats, and then care for it daily by logging into FooPets.com from a computer or m.foopets.com from a mobile device. Every pet's scene or room can be customized with backgrounds, toys and accessories, some of these can be earned by logging into FooPets.com frequently. 

For children under 13, FooPets offers a limited feature set and web site experience. For these younger children, a number of social features are disabled including chat, messaging, posting to forums, profile descriptions, profile photo uploading, pet descriptions and sending and reading messages with gifts. Some advanced features like owning multiple pets, buying Breeding Licenses, and breeding pets are disabled. Additionally, FooDollars, the virtual currency within the FooPets community, which holds monetary value, cannot be earned or purchased (until child is a member of ClubFoo). In order to gain access to ALL of these communication and commerce features, parental consent is required via a parent or guardian approved child membership to ClubFoo, a premium membership club. ClubFoo members have access to a complete set of FooPets features. 

In this policy we describe what information we collect, how we collect it, and what we do with it (the policy covers only information collected and used on FooPets.com and FooPets applications on social networks such as Facebook and MySpace). Rivet Games makes every effort to comply with the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act, (COPPA) a U.S. law that governs the use and collection of information online from children under 13. To learn more about COPPA, and about how to protect your children online, please visit http://www.ftc.gov/privacy/coppafaqs.shtm for information from the U.S. Federal Trade Commission, as well as http://www.onguardonline.gov/socialnetworking_youth.html. 

This Privacy Policy (this "Policy") explains how personal information is safely handled by www.FooPets.com and all other Rivet Games, Inc. web sites, applications and portals. FooPets.com provides a fun and safe virtual experience for everyone. 

Rivet Games, Inc. is a licensee of the TRUSTe Children's Online Privacy Seal Program. TRUSTe is an independent, organization whose mission is to build user's trust and confidence in the Internet by promoting the use of fair information practices. This privacy statement covers the site www.foopets.com. Because this Web site wants to demonstrate its commitment to your privacy, it has agreed to disclose its information practices and have its privacy practices reviewed for compliance by TRUSTe. 

If you have questions or concerns regarding this statement, you should first contact a FooPets Support Representative at support@foopets.com. If you do not receive acknowledgement of your inquiry or your inquiry has not been satisfactorily addressed, you should contact TRUSTe at http://watchdog.truste.com/pvr.php?page=complaint&url. TRUSTe will then serve as a liaison with us to resolve your concerns. 

### What is Personal Information?

Personal information specifically identifies an individual with a name, address, city, state, zip code, telephone number, e-mail address, passwords, credit card or other account number—and may include information about that individual's FooPets activities and account. Personal information also includes demographic data, such as date of birth, gender, geographic area and preferences when linked to other personal information that identifies an individual. 

Personal information does not include "aggregate" information. Aggregate information is data collected about a group or category of products, services or customers from which individual customer identities have been removed. In other words, information about how you use a service may be collected and combined with information about how others use the same service, but no personal information will be included in the resulting data. 

### Personal Information We Collect

When people, including those under 13, register and create a FooPets account, we collect a set of information. For those registering on FooPets (including those under 13), we will collect and protect the following personal information: 

  * Screen Name (visible to other members of FooPets, registrant is prompted to not use real name)
  * Password (required for login)
  * Email (if registrant is under 13, they're prompted to provide email of parent or guardian)
  * Date Of Birth (required to retrieve lost password)
  * Gender

Please note: when a child under 13 registers on FooPets, they are required to provide an email address of a parent or guardian. FooPets uses the parent or guardian's email address provided at registration to notify parents that their children have adopted a pet and created an account on FooPets.com. In that email, parents are provided: 

  * Details about what information their child used to register on FooPets.com and parents can choose to edit this information at any time
  * Details on how their children can use FooPets.com and a link to this privacy policy
  * Information about ClubFoo and directions on how parents can provide consent to "unlock" a variety of communication and commerce features for their child via registering their child for ClubFoo, our premium membership club for FooPets members
  * Details on how parent email addresses are used to communicate with parents about their child in relation to their child's pet and activity at FooPets.com such as pet alert emails, forgotten password reminders and FooDollar notifications (for children that are members of ClubFoo)
  * A link to disable and remove a child's profile (and associated information) from FooPets.com and FooPets applications, should parent chose to remove their child from the FooPets community

Upon completion of a registration, information submitted will be used by FooPets to create an account, adopt a pet and will allow the registered user to participate on the FooPets.com website, which contains a variety of interactive and community features (as mentioned above, all social features are disabled for children under 13 until FooPets receives parental consent via registering their child in ClubFoo). 

FooPet owners can make friends with other FooPet owners by visiting another member's profile. In this scenario, a friend request is sent from one FooPet owner to another, and the recipient of the friend request has the ability to accept or decline that friend request. If the recipient accepts the request, the two will show as "friends" on each other's profile, but they will not be able to communicate via Chat or web site messaging until they're both members of ClubFoo. Free-form text features are only available to members of ClubFoo. Free form text features on FooPets include: sending/receiving/reading messages, posting to forums, editing profile descriptions and editing Foto descritptions. For additional information on how our site operates, please read our Parent's Page. 

The FooPets e-card greeting feature collects information about 3rd parties such as name and email address. We use this information to facilitate sending mail, and that it is not used for any other purpose other than it was collected. 

When completing a financial transaction on FooPets.com, for parents and those 18 and older, we will collect and protect the following information:

  * Credit card number, expiration, cvs code
  * Billing name, address, city, state, zip/postal code, country

Important Note: Any child, including children in ClubFoo, can be identified by their Screen Name within the FooPets community. As such, it is advised that children (and all FooPets members) do not use their real name as their Screen Name or publish their real name anywhere on their profile or in the Forums. Additionally, real names should not be used in any public communication area where identity can be disclosed in connection with a member's information, comments, passwords, etc. If real names are used (or Screen Names include any personally identifying information as part of a "nickname" or anywhere on your profile) that information will be publicly displayed on our site. Therefore, please use caution in determining your Screen Name and identity on the site. 

We do not collect "sensitive data" that pertains to racial or ethnic origins, political or religious beliefs, or health or sex life. 

We enable you to invite your Gmail, Yahoo, AOL, Hotmail, LinkedIn, and other contacts to join FooPets.com. We will display your contacts from any address book(s) of your choice. You can also text input addresses. We will send out the invitations on your behalf. However, we do not store these email addresses in any database or repository. 

Parents and legal guardians of children under 13 who are members of FooPets.com have certain rights under COPPA, and FooPets recognizes those rights. Parents/guardians can consent to collection and use of a child's personally identifiable information (PII) without consenting to the disclosure of information to third parties. Currently the only identifiable information we collect from children under 13 is parent's email address. We will not knowingly grant access to social features on FooPets.com without parental consent and that child's membership in ClubFoo. If a parent does not provide consent, we will not grant that child access to social and communication features on FooPets.com. 

Parents/guardians can review information their children have contributed to FooPets.com, by accessing their child's account (login instructions are included in the "Direct Notice" email sent to all parents/guardians following their under 13 child's registration on FooPets). Parents can also request that FooPets delete that information and refuse to allow FooPets to collect further information from their children by contacting our Customer Service department by email at support@foopets.com. Parents should include their children's Screen Name and the registered (parent's) email address in the email so we can better assist them with their inquiry or request. FooPets may ask additional questions or take other steps to verify the identity of parents/guardians before responding to a request to review or delete their child's information, or a request to refuse further collection from children. 

A child's participation or access to an activity on FooPets cannot be conditioned on her providing more information than is reasonably necessary for that activity, or any personally identifiable information. FooPets does not collect personally identifiable information from children under 13, without a parent or guardian's consent. 

### Why We Collect Personal Information

FooPets is an interactive gaming and social networking application and requires a valid email address correlated with the user name(s) in order to become a FooPet owner. We use this information to send you pet related notifications and alerts, and links that can be used to activate your account. We also send a weekly newsletter to update you on our latest offerings, promotions and news. You can opt-out of any or all emails at any time on your preferences page. 

We authenticate with email addresses, usernames and passwords to enable proper access to users' accounts. We also monitor usage to make sure FooPets owners are following the Terms and Conditions of our site. Monitoring in this manner is intended to protect our community members and preserve a safe, fair, and positive experience for everyone. We may use an email address to temporarily or permanently ban a person from playing on FooPets if inappropriate and disruptive conduct ensues. 

As mentioned above, we request additional personally identifiable information from members wanting to complete financial transactions for added features and services that we may offer. 

We may also use information in an aggregate form to analyze site patterns and usage to assist in creating new features, products, programs or services. For some of our activities (polls or surveys), we may ask users to provide information that is not personally identifiable (e.g. favorite animal, top dog breeds, etc.) 

When a username or email address is requested from FooPets via FooPets.com a form is submitted through our 'contact us' page, blogs, forums or wiki area of our website. This ensures that we provide a response in a timely manner, or track and monitor correspondence that may be deemed inappropriate or disturbing to the community. 

We may passively collect certain non-personally identifiable computer information such as the type of operating system (Windows 7, Mac OS), the user's IP address, type of web browser (Internet Explorer, Firebox, Safari) and information regarding the Internet service provider used, and possibly link this information to the user account and personal information. If we do this, we will secure this data. 

We may also use Cookies. Cookies are small text files that we place in visitors' computer browsers to store their preferences. You can choose to have your computer warn you each time a cookie is being sent, or you can choose to turn off all cookies. You do this through your browser (Internet Explorer, Firefox, Safari) settings. Each browser is a little different, so look at your browser Help menu to learn the correct way to modify your cookies. If you turn cookies off, you won't have access to many features that make your Web experience smoother, and some of our services may not function properly. 

Third parties that we link to from our site may use cookies but we are not responsible and/or liable for the use of cookies by such third parties and they are not covered by our privacy policy. 

Lastly, we collect financial or payment information used for no other purpose than processing payments to Rivet Games, Inc. The financial information entered to acquire a membership is not stored by Rivet Games, but is instead retained by our payments processing vendor Cybersource specifically to securely manage credit card payments made to Rivet Games, Inc. 

If personal information is not provided but necessary to create an account, then Rivet Games, Inc. may not agree to membership and may not be able to provide access to certain areas and functionality on the FooPet website(s), application(s), or portal(s) or provide information, products, or services that may be requested. 

In case of a merger or business transfer, a sale or transfer of our assets, or if we sell all or part of our business, we may transfer personal information to a third party as part of that business transaction to the extent permitted by law. 

### How We Collect and Process Your Information

All personal information is processed fairly and lawfully. We ask for consent before collecting personal information, and disclose when it is collected and how the data will be used. We do not ask for information that is out of scope of the purpose for which it is collected. In addition, the use of personal information is not used beyond what has been disclosed. Participants that provide personal information can later view, change any inaccuracies, or delete their data at any time. 

### What We Don't Do

We know how intrusive it is to get spam, unsolicited phone calls, and 'junk' mail. This is why we will not contact you unless you specifically request to be contacted. The log in area is designed to provide visitors with FooPet and company information that requires email verification and proper internal approval within Rivet Games. We do not share, rent, or sell this information with any person, business, or organization. 

Other areas of our website, specifically our applications, enable visitors to experience the fun, convenience, and excitement of FooPets. Information entered in these sections will not be permanently stored and/or used, nor will it be exposed or exploited through Rivet Games or any third party affiliate or otherwise. This information will not be shared, sold, or rented to any person, business organization. If you have any questions about our email policies, please feel free to contact us at contact@foopets.com. 

### Sharing of Personal Information

We do not sell, rent, or share personal information to any person, business, or organization without your prior consent except in the limited circumstances described in this Policy. 

We will disclose personal information when we believe it is appropriate to comply with the law (e.g., a lawful subpoena, warrant, or court order) or at the request of law enforcement authorities or as a result of the unlawful use of our site. If we reasonably believe that an emergency involving danger of serious physical injury or death to any person(s) requires disclosure of communications or records, we will use reasonable commercial efforts to disclose this information promptly. In addition, information about our customers including personally identifiable information may be disclosed as part of any merger, acquisition, debt financing or sale of company assets, as well as in the event of an insolvency, bankruptcy or receivership in which personally identifiable information could be transferred to third parties as one of our business assets. 

### Information Shared With Other Users

Your account information is displayed to other users in your FooPet profile. This information may also be available through automated script calls and application program interfaces. This information includes your Screen Name, FooPet(s) name(s), FooDollars and StarPoints information (quantities). We do not display your address, credit card number, or bank account numbers. 

You may choose to disclose your own personal information in our online forums, or wikis. Please be aware that this information is public and therefore not held confidential or private in these settings. 

### Security

The information you submit to this Website is stored in encrypted form. We follow generally accepted industry standards to protect data both in transmission and when we hold it. However, no means of transmission or method of electronic storage is 100% secure so whilst we strive to use commercially acceptable means to protect data we cannot guarantee its security. 

### Changes in this Privacy Statement

If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes to this privacy statement, the homepage, and other places we deem appropriate so that you are aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it. 

We reserve the right to modify this privacy statement at any time, so please review it frequently. If we make material changes to how we use Personal Information collected from children under age 13, we will notify parents by email in order to obtain verifiable parental consent for the new uses of the child's Personal Information. 

### How to Contact Us

If you have further questions and comments on privacy please contact us at:

Rivet Games, Inc.   
625 2nd St, Suite 104  
San Francisco, CA 94107  
USA 

Support: 

email: support@foopets.com 

phone: +1.415.625.0032 

#### ©2011 Rivet Games, Inc. All rights reserved.

Top
